# **Surasak Watthanayontkit**

1414/205 Sukhumvit Road, Phra Khanong, Klong Tuey, Bangkok 10110 +66 81 697 4290 • <a href="mailto:swatth-429">swatthanayontkit@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/swatth-429">https://github.com/swatth</a>

......

#### SUMMARY

Software developer/designer with over 20 years of working experiences in various industries, including Oil & Gas, Financial, and Banking involving Retail and Core Banking, IT Service Management Suite (ITIL certified), chatbot (focusing on LINE platform), B2B e-Commerce, risk screening services and Online Travelling Agency.

Special Interests in Data Sciences/Machine Learning, Supply Chain Management

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: Java, Python, Scala, COBOL, Assembler both x86 and S/390 (a.k.a. Mainframe) and some analytics tools i.e., R, SPARK (Scala) and tech. related to Software Development i.e. SQLDB (MS-SQL, Postgres), NoSQL (MongoDB), XML (including XPath and XSLT transform) HTTP-Based APIs (SOAP, REST)
- Familiarity with cloud technologies with a number of certifications for Azure, AWS, and GCP
- Experiences on leading a software development team both with Agile framework (<u>PMI-ACP certified</u>) and traditional one (waterfall)
- Experiences on managing IT Service Management System Suites (ITSM) and its integration to automation systems (ITIL certified: license no. <u>GR677000595SW</u>)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## CPF IT Center:AXONS (Sep 2023 – Present)

Development Manager Overseeing ~20 developers responsible for consumer products focusing on POS solutions used in retailers/restaurants, including web portal to manage subscriptions. Technologies used range from .NET, React (Next.js), Java SpringBoot, Flutter, Node.js on Azure and aws cloud.

## Agoda (Aug 2021 – Jun 2023)

 Senior Software/Data Engineer responsible for developing/supporting Hotel booking pricing platform hosted on both VM (containerized) and Kubernetes (~100M total bookings in 2022) – with special focus on Cashback program using Scala (HTTP APIs with JSON and gRPCs with Protobuf), Apache Kafka, Apache Hadoop/Spark, MS SQL DB

## Thai Military Thanachart Bank Public Company Limited (Jun 2021 – Jul 2021)

Solutions Architect responsible for guiding a team of 4-5 members as well as designing/implementing PoC of a
mobile app service for bank customers with insurance/lease account with the bank to facilitate second-hand car
sales using Java SpringBoot, Redis, Apache Kafka, and SQL DB

## Refinitiv Software (Thailand)/London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) (Nov 2020 - May 2021)

• Lead Software Engineer responsible for developing, supporting and leading a team of 2-3 members of backend part of risk screening service developed using Java SpringBoot and MongoDB on AWS Cloud Platform.

#### FutureSkill.co (Aug 2019: Freelance)

• Content creator and Instructor of the e-learning course: <u>Machine Learning with Object Classification</u> (taught in Thai targeting beginners as intended audiences covering Python and Keras – now part of TensorFlow package)

#### ExxonMobil Limited (Jan 2006 - Oct 2020)

#### Mar 2020 - Oct 2020

- Software Development on SAP Commerce Platform (Hybris) involving Java and Spring framework on Java 6.
   Oct 2019 Mar 2020
- Software Development involving App Modernization by converting Java 6 with Spring framework to Java 8 SpringBoot with Hibernates, Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform, Jenkins.

## ExxonMobil Limited (Continued)

### Dec 2018 - Sep 2019

- Led a development/tech support team of 2-3 members of LINE Chatbot for Esso Thailand Line Channel with 2M+ active users and average 10k+ messages/day. using Node.js/Vue.js on MS Azure Cloud Platform.
- Improved a deployment process of LINE chatbot to be automated and under blue-green deployment approach using Azure DevOps (former names: Microsoft Team Foundation Server/Visual Studio Team Server)
   Jan 2009 – Nov 2018
- Occasionally led the team adopting agile framework as a Scrum Master (team size ranging from 7-12 members)
- Development (customization) and support IT Service Manage Suite (100k internal users with 2M+ tickets annually) focusing on Request Fulfillment Services as well as automating their back-end portions.
- Led the backend interface transition of Customer Service Application used by Fuels Marketing Customer Services from legacy SAP/R2 on mainframe to SAP/R3 with additional interfaces to SAS, IBM DB/2, and MS-SQL Server Jan 2006 – Dec 2009
- Supported Payment Card Authorization System related to Retail Service stations all over AP countries (Singapore, Malaysia, Hong Kong, Macau, Guam and Saipan)

## IBM Thailand Company Limited (Nov 2002 - Sep 2003)

Maintained and enhanced the IBM's SAFE II core banking application package residing on IBM Mainframe platform

## Skill Power Services (Thailand) Company Limited (Jul 2001 - Oct 2002)

Same roles as the position working at IBM Thailand (Described above)

## Bangkok Bank Public Company Limited (Jun 2000 - Jun 2001)

- Developed a back-end program to handle Cash-Deposit Machine (ATM-like machine but for money deposit instead)
- Maintained and enhanced the ACI BASE-24 package (an Automatic Teller Machine package program used on the host-side with 300k+ financial transactions daily)
- Participated in the hardware upgrading of the HP Nonstop/TANDEM platform (used as a host of the ATM system)

## **EDUCATION**

2020

Deep Learning Nanodegree from Udacity (certification link <a href="here">here</a>)

2018

Supply Chain Management MicroMasters from MITx through edX (program record <u>here</u>, more details in <u>this program</u> <u>letter</u>)

2004 - 2005

Australian National University, MSE (Master of Software Engineering)

1996 - 2000

King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, B.Eng. (Bachelor of Computer Engineering)

#### **INTERESTS**

#### **iOS Development Hobbyist**

 Created the app: <u>Meet-Thi-13</u> to demonstrate the application of CNN (Convolutional Neural Networks) on Image Classifier to real-world use case.

#### **MOOCs**

- Completed nearly 100 courses since 2014 via Coursera, eDX, Udacity, and Udemy covering a wide range of topics including businesses (MBA level), Data Sciences/Big Data Analytics, and Machine Learning. (details on personal Facebook Photo Albums: link to stand-alone course certificates and link to programme certificates)
- Served as a Community TA in Python Programming course offered by MIT via eDX

#### **Technical Speaker**

• Speaker in PyCon Thailand 2018: Deep Learning in the Household

(More details on references available upon request)